There's just nothing down there.
这儿还真是荒凉
I haven't seen a building in, like, 20 minutes.
我已经有20分钟没见到任何人烟了
-Look at that. -We're not on vacation, Hap.
-看看这地方 -我们可不是来度假的，哈普
Cheer up, will you?
精神点好嘛？
Tell that to her, partner.
这话就对她说吧，拍档
Better hang on, guys. It's gonna get rough.
坐稳，我们马上要降落了
Detective Eckhart, Detective Ellie Burr.
艾克哈特探员， 我是埃莉布勒探员
-Hi. -Nice to meet you.
-嗨 -很高兴见到你
How are you doing?
你好吗？
" Halibut fishing capital of the world." Okay.
“大比目鱼捕捞胜地” 了不起
Detective Dormer, it's an honor to meet you.
多默探员，能见到您真是荣幸
Welcome to Nightmute. I got the car right here.
欢迎来到寂夜镇 车子就在那边
It's so incredible to be working with you.
能和您一起共事实在是太棒了
I've followed all of your cases: Theodore Dineli, Frank Prud'homme...
我研究过你所破的所有案件： 西奥多迪内里，弗兰克普劳姆…
...the Ocean Park shootings and especially the Leland Street murders.
…海洋公园枪击案 尤其是里兰大道谋杀案
Is that where Ronald Langley cut you, at 325 Leland Street?
罗纳德兰利是在325里兰大道袭击你的吗？
You did your homework.
你知道的还真不少
The Leland Street murders was my case study at the academy.
里兰大道谋杀案 是我在警校学过的案例
-I'll take you to the Lodge and-- -No, take us to the station.
-现在我就送你们去住处-- -不用，直接带我们警局吧
Right. We need to get started.
没错，我们应该马上开始
Most homicides are solved in the first 72 hours.
多数杀人犯都是在 最初72小时内被抓获的
Well, it's 48 hours. We're a day behind.
那就只剩48小时了 来这儿我们已经花了一天
But who's counting?
不过谁管它呢？
Yeah, come in.
快进来
They got you behind a desk, huh? Charlie Bubbles. How you doing?
你都坐上这位置了 查理巴勃，你还好吗？
-I haven't seen you since when? -Hey, Charlie.
-我们有多久没见了？ -你好，查理
-Seven years? -Eight.
-七年？ -是八年
Seven years! I am old. Ellie, get everyone in the bullpen.
是七年！我已经老了 埃莉，叫大伙儿都准备好
-Nice kid. -Loves the job.
-这孩子不错 -很敬业
When I called Buck for advice on this, I never expected he'd send you up here.
我给布克电话请求协助时 从没想到他居然舍得把你派来
-Something about lnternal Affairs? -They're moving in.
-对你的内部调查怎么样了？ -还在查
It's nothing. It's the usual crap. Buck figured you could use some help--
没什么，不过是例行公事 布克觉得你需要帮助--
They got Finn and Kentor on Narcotics.
他们派芬和肯托去复查毒品案
The fuckers are looking for headlines--
那些混蛋是想没事找碴--
-It's gonna blow over. -Got a message from Warfield.
-事情会过去的 -沃菲尔德给我来了电话
I.A.'s pit bull.
内部调查员就只会咬自己人
He wants to be posted on your movements.
他要我汇报你的一举一动
You'll find us more straightforward.
你会发现这里的人要单纯些
Good guys, bad guys, but a lot less public relations. It's simple.
只有好人和坏人，没有勾心斗角
Except for this.
除了这桩案子
Okay, listen up. Detectives Dormer and Eckhart...
大家听好了 多默探员和艾克哈特探员
...on loan from Buck Lundgard, L.A. Homicide.
是从洛杉矶凶案科调来的
They'll help with the Connell case.
他们会协助我们调查这桩康内尔案
Anything they want to see, show them. Anyplace they want to go, take them.
他们想看什么就给他们看 想去哪里就带他们去
This is Fred Duggar. He's heading the investigation.
这位是佛瑞德杜格 这案子由他负责调查
-A pleasure. -Want to get on it?
-很荣幸 -有什么进展？
-Seen what we got? -Let's start with the body.
-要看我们的调查报告吗？ -就从调查尸体开始
-You got the report? -I want to see for myself.
-需要验尸报告？ -我要亲眼看看尸体
Herniation of the brain stem due to intracerebral hemorrhage.
颅内出血导致脑干成疝
-Beaten to death. -These contusions?
-是被钝物敲击至死 -那这些伤痕呢？
Superficial. Most of the trauma was to her face and neck.
都是些表皮淤痕 多数集中在脸部和颈部
-Any signs of rape? -No.
-有遭受强奸的迹象吗？ -没有
-This one covers an older bruise. -There's an older one here.
-这儿有块旧伤 -这儿也有
-They're both in the report. -He washed her hair.
-这些都在报告里说了 -凶手还洗了她的头
Scrubbed her nails.
剔净了她的指甲
It's all in the report.
报告上什么都有
-Doesn't say he clipped them. -She could have clipped them.
-怎么就没写上凶手剪掉了指甲 -应该是她自己剪的
Nope. No polish on the ends of the nails. See?
错了，注意没有？ 指甲的末端剪的并不平整
She painted them herself. Someone else cut them. Toes too.
她涂上了指甲油 而另外有人剪掉了指甲，脚趾甲也一样
-Naked when found? -Yeah. Last seen wearing a red dress.
-发现尸体时是裸体吗？ -是的，最后见她的时候穿着红色外套
No fibers, flakes, hairs?
没有发现任何毛发和皮屑吗？
We know about forensics work here. The body gave us nothing.
我们已经做了仔细的调查 这尸体上没留下什么线索
She gave us plenty. All this trouble, all this care. Why?
她留给我们很多线索 为何凶手要那么麻烦把尸体清理干净？
-He knew her. -He knows we can connect him to her.
-因为他认识她 -他知道我们会找到他头上
This isn't a random psycho? Crime of passion?
这会不会是乱性杀人？性犯罪？
Maybe. But whatever happened, his reaction wasn't passionate.
可能吧，不过不管是怎么回事 他的反应并不象是失去控制
He didn't panic. Didn't chop her up or burn her.
他没有惊慌 没有把尸体砍碎或是烧毁
He just thought about what we would be looking for...
他只是考虑了我们可能会发现什么
...and then calmly removed all those traces.
然后冷静的消除所有的证据
No haste. No rush.
不慌不忙的消除
Why clip the nails after scrubbing them?
为什么在剔净指甲后 还要再剪掉它们？
Manipulating the body. Prolonging the moment.
是在制造假象，拖延时间
No mutilation.
没有切除尸体的其他部分
Not this time.
不是说这次
-You think there's been others? -No.
-你觉得还有其他的并发案？ -不
But there's gonna be. This guy...
但将来还会发生的，这个家伙
...he crossed the line and he didn't even blink.
他作案的时候甚至都不眨下眼睛
You don't come back from that.
你们不用管这些
Okay. Let's go find out who Kay was.
好，就让我们来查下这个凯的背景
Fred said not to touch anything, so I haven't tidied up.
佛瑞德说什么也别碰 所以我也没收拾过屋子
She hates it when I go into her room anyway.
她很讨厌我进她房间
Thank you, Mrs. Connell.
谢谢，康纳尔太太
So she went to a party Friday night.
那么她周五晚上去参加了聚会
Not exactly a party. It's a local dive where the kids hang out.
准确的说并不是聚会 只是个本地小孩常去的酒吧
No diary?
没有日记吗？
We didn't find one. Her mom said she has a journal.
我们没有找到，她母亲说她写
Friends said she argued with her boyfriend Friday.
朋友们说她周五和男朋友吵架了
She stormed off just after midnight.
午夜后就失踪了
She did, huh?
是她撕的？
This is interesting.
真有趣
Who is this?
这是谁？
Tanya Francke, Kay's best friend.
坦尼娅弗兰基，她是凯最好的朋友
I want to talk to her.
我想要和她谈谈
Who is Kay Connell? Who is she? Is she popular or is she a loner?
凯康内尔是谁？她是怎样的人？ 交游广阔或是生性孤僻？
Did she like this town? She want to bolt first chance she got?
她喜欢这个镇子吗？ 一有机会她就会离开这里吗？
Did she have dreams?
她有梦想吗？
She knew this guy. We know her, maybe we can know him.
她熟悉凶手 而我们通过熟悉她，或许可以找到案犯
This is designer. This is expensive.
这见衣服款式新颖，定很昂贵
-The boyfriend, Randy. -Randy Stetz.
-她的男朋友是叫兰迪吧 -兰迪史特兹
-He could afford this? -He's in school.
-他买的起这个吗？ -他还是学生
-Mom didn't buy it. -What are we thinking?
-她妈妈也不会买 -什么意思？
I don't know, stepfather? Any rich uncles?
我不知道，或许是继父买的？ 某个有钱的叔叔？
No.
没有这种关系
An admirer.
有个追求她的人
Yeah.
是的
-I want the boyfriend. -I'll get him to the station.
-我想要找他的男朋友 -我会叫他去警局
I want to go to the school. Pull him out in front of friends.
不，我想去学校找他 面对面的和他谈谈
Catch him off guard. It will get people talking.
把他用警车架走会惹来人们的闲话
So how far away is the school?
那么学校有多远？
-It's 1 0:00, Detective Dormer. -You bet.
-现在是十点，多默探员 -那又怎么样
At night.
现在是晚上十点
So when does it get dark here?
那这儿的天什么时候黑？
It doesn't.
不会黑
Not this time of year.
每年这时候都不会黑
Yeah, I heard about that. How come you didn't know that, Hap?
没错，我听说过 你怎么就没想到呢，哈普？
-Lower 48. -Lower 48?
-是从下面的州来的吧 -下面的州？
Not from here. Can tell by your walk.
你们不是本州人 从走路的样子就看的出来
-How's that? -Unsure.
-怎么个样子？ -很不自信
Dormer and Eckhart. We have a reservation.
多默和艾克哈特，我们已经预定了房间
Don't be fooled by my friend's frivolous demeanor. He's all business.
别被这家伙的轻率愚弄了，他狡猾着呢
-Your restaurant still serving? -Kitchen's about to close.
-餐厅还在营业吗？ -厨房马上就要关了
We'll be quick. Thank you.
我们会快点吃的，谢谢
Thanks.
谢了
We got the Halibut Calabrese, got the Halibut Olympian.
菜谱上有大比目鱼甘蓝花， 大比目鱼大餐
-Keep going. -Halibut Cajun style.
-还有呢 -大比目鱼法式料理
I can't wait to see what they got for dessert.
真想知道餐后甜点会上些什么
Natives are getting restless.
我们好象打搅了别人
-We gotta talk. -No, we don't.
-我们得要谈谈 -没这个必要
-Just sit tight? -Nothing's changed.
-就这么干坐着？ -反正就是老样子
Nothing's changed?
老样子？
What do you think we're doing in the halibut capital of the world?
那你觉得我们来这个 “大比目鱼捕捞胜地”干什么？
Buck figured Charlie needed help.
布克觉得查理需要帮助
Buck figured l.A. would be coming to me next, and he was right.
布克觉得内部调查员接下来会找我 他料的没错
Warfield had me in his office for three hours yesterday.
沃菲尔德昨天把我 叫到他办公室三个小时
Hap, he's rattling your cage, pal. That's all.
哈普，他只想探你的口风 没什么的
Me and Trish talked it through, and I'm sorry, I gotta cut a deal.
我和崔西商量过了 很抱歉，我只得接受交易
-Don't say this shit to me. -You won't be involved.
-别对我说这种混帐话 -不会影响到你
I'm not? Of course I will.
不会？当然我会受牵连
With your reputation, he can't touch you.
你的名声在外，他不会动你的
My reputation's the whole problem.
就因为我的名声才是问题
You think Warfield gives a fuck about you shaking down drug dealers?
你以为沃菲尔德会在乎你干掉了毒贩？
You think that will get him his headlines? He needs the big fish.
你以为他的目标就只是这？ 他要的是大鱼
He's putting the squeeze on you to get to me.
他在通过你给我施加压力
-But you're clean, Will. -I'm a good cop, yeah.
-但你是清白的，威尔 -对，我是个好警察
But there's always something they could use to get at your credibility.
但他们总会找到些东西来起诉我
Have you any idea what this is gonna do?
你知道事情会怎样发展？
Think about all my cases. All the cases dependent on my word, my judgment.
他们会让你回想我办的所有案件 认为那些案件都是我在捏造证词
Those fuckers on the street. That's what you're doing.
所以那些杂碎们又可以回大街上逍遥了 那就是你正在做的蠢事
They got nothing on you because there's nothing to get.
你清清白白，怕他们找什么证据
Dobbs.
道比斯的案子
-What about Dobbs? -That's different.
-道比斯怎么样？ -那不同
It's different?
怎么不同？
Warfield doesn't want Dobbs on the street.
即便是沃菲尔德也不愿意见到 道比斯这种杂碎回到街上
It's a house of cards. Once it starts, it's just gonna tumble. All of it.
这就象是多米诺骨牌 只要一张倒了，就全盘皆输
That's a chance I gotta take, pal.
这机会我一定要把握，伙计
-I got family. -Don't give me that.
-我还有家人 -别这么对我
Warfield made it clear. I get probation.
沃菲尔德说的很清楚 那样我会得到留用查看的机会
We're cops, man. This is not about us.
我们都是警察 这么做并不是为了我们自己
This is about all the people who depend on us. People with families.
而是为了所有依赖我们的人 那些有家的人们
I spent my life doing this. My life.
我一辈子都为了这目标兢兢业业
You're gonna destroy it like that. Why? Why?
而你却要将之毁坏 这是为什么？为什么？
So some l.A. prick gets closer to being chief of police?
你这样帮那垃圾是在助纣为虐
Or playing golf with the mayor or whatever the fuck else he's after?
他是想当警局的头儿？ 还是想和市长能打上高尔夫球？
You finished?
说完了吗？
Sorry, I gotta cut a deal.
对不起，我只能接受交易
So, make any decisions?
决定点什么了吗？
-You do everything around here? -After 1 1, pretty much.
-这儿什么都由你来做吗？ -11点后就是如此
Over to you, Will. What are you having?
还是你决定吧，威尔 你想要来点什么？
I lost my appetite.
我没胃口
Excuse me.
抱歉
Morning.
早上好
-What kind of calls you get here? -Mostly drinking-related problems.
-平时都处理些什么案子？ -大部分都是酒后滋事
Domestic abuse, bar fights, that sort of stuff.
或是家庭暴力，酒吧殴斗什么的
People here come to live the way they want to...
这儿的人都生活的很悠闲
...so most people keep to themselves.
所以也就很少对自己有约束
Chief won't let me handle anything over a misdemeanor.
局长都让我处理些无关紧要的小案子
Don't knock misdemeanors.
别小看那些小案子
No, but it's such small stuff. It's so boring.
不是小看，那些实在是很琐碎 让人烦透了
It's all about small stuff. You know, small lies, small mistakes.
任何犯罪都是由小开始 撒个小谎，犯个小错
People give themselves away same in misdemeanors as in murder cases.
无论是在轻罪或是谋杀案中 人们都是同样的放纵自己
It's just human nature. Aren't you gonna write that down?
这就是人的本性 要把这记下来吗？
Friends making you nervous? They think you did it?
朋友们的眼光使你不安了？ 他们怀疑是你做的吗？
You killed her?
觉得是你杀了她？
-No smoking on the school premises. -Did you love her?
-学校里别抽烟 -你爱她吗？
-Randy, did you love her? -Sure, she was nice.
-兰迪，你爱她吗？ -当然，她是个好姑娘
She was nice. Wow. That makes me all soft inside.
“她是个好姑娘” 这话让我听来舒服不少
Did it occur to you she didn't love you?
那使你觉得她并不爱你吗？
She loved me.
她爱我
-Wanted me every night. -Probably to pass the time.
-每天晚上都想我 -也许后来已经变了
Girl like Kay Connell, she was looking for more than some loser. Right?
象凯康内尔这样的女孩 她会找些比差生更值得爱的
What can I say? Love is blind.
我能说什么？爱是盲目的
-Live on your own? -His grandpa's.
-自己生活吗？ -和他爷爷住
-No alibi for Friday? -Didn't know I'd need one.
-有不在现场证明吗？ -不觉得我需要
-At the party what'd you fight about? -Stuff. No big deal.
-听说你的聚会上打了她？ -不过是小事
-I heard it was a loud fight. -I guess.
-可我听说打的很厉害 -可能吧
-I heard it was pretty rough. -lt wasn't rough.
-听说你当时的行为很粗野 -并不粗野
Not like the other times. Those times she wouldn't listen to you.
因为这次不同了，她并不愿意听你的
Couldn't keep her mouth shut.
你没办法让她闭嘴
-Keep fishing, man. -We saw the bruises.
-扯你的吧，老头 -我们在她身上发现了伤痕
They said she was beaten.
他们说她是被殴至死
Not those bruises. Come on. The old bruises. Your bruises.
不是那些伤，是旧伤 是你打起的
I'm sick of this. I haven't done anything wrong.
我受够了，我没做什么错事
You haven't?
真的没有吗？
Fuck you!
操你的！
You're a prick in a leather jacket. What the fuck do you know?
你这个穿皮夹克的垃圾 你他妈懂什么？
Randy...
兰迪
...this whole thing you're doing, this fuck-the-world act.
你所玩的这套 这套玩世不恭的把戏
It might work with your mom. It might even work with local cops...
可能对你妈有用 或是对本地的警察有用
...who know you enough to figure you're too dumb to kill...
他们认为你没有能力干净的杀了人
...without leaving witnesses and a signed confession.
而不留下任何线索 所以就放你一马
It ain't gonna work with me.
可这套对我没用
Because I know things. You understand?
因为我清楚一切，明白吗？
I know you beat your girlfriend.
我知道你打了你女朋友
I know she was seeing somebody else.
我知道她在和别人约会
Someone she might have gone to see after she walked out on you Friday.
周五她甩开你就是要和那人约会
Now are you gonna tell us who that somebody might be?
现在不如就老实告诉我们 那人究竟是谁？
Or are you so fucking stupid...
或者我想你不会愚蠢到
...you're gonna leave yourself as the last person to see Kay Connell alive?
把自己的性命留给杀了凯的人来取吧？
I don't know.
我不知道
You don't know.
你不知道
I couldn't get her to tell me.
她死活不肯告诉我
How hard did you try?
你很努力的去试了吗？
Pretty hard.
非常努力
-You think he.... -No.
-你觉得他… -不
How'd it go? Find where this is from.
去查查这是从哪儿来的
Mrs. Connell and her friends don't know.
我问过了康内尔太太和她的朋友们 都说不知道
You try the jewelry stores? Small things, remember?
查过珠宝店了吗？ 不要小看小事，记得吗？
The second you're about to dismiss something, think about it.
要放弃某件事的时候就再想想
Look at it again.
再多看一遍
Want me to write that down?
要我记下来吗？
No, I'll remember it.
不，我会记得的
-Where was it? -ln a cabin on the beach.
-是在哪儿发现的？ -一间海滩边的小屋
-It's Kay's? -Her books are in it.
-是凯的吗？ -她的书都在里面
-Kids found it. -Cabin secured?
-是小孩们发现的 -小屋那边现在怎么样？
-Francis is headed there. -Stop him.
-弗兰西斯正守在那儿 -叫他回来
-Tell him to stay clear. -Rich.
-别留下什么痕迹 -里奇
Biology and Algebra.
生物和代数
Let's find out who she studied with, where she bought this.
我们要知道她跟谁学 她从哪儿买的这个
" Otherwise Engaged. A J. Brody mystery."
“ AJ.布罗迪密斯特里”
-Who reads this crap? -I do.
-谁喜欢看书？ -我
Read it. After it's dusted.
化验以后拿去读读
Find anything that strikes you, plot-wise, underlined passages.
找到任何引起你注意的部分 情节上的，被标注的语句
There it is. The diary.
日记原来在这里
Every word.
每句话都要看仔细
That's it.
都在这儿了
-I'll put it in evidence. -No.
-我会把这送去证物间 -不
Why?
为什么？
Call every radio station from here to Anchorage.
给从这儿到安克雷奇的所有电台打电话
Tell them we're looking for the bag Kay left the party with.
对他们说我们在寻找 凯遗忘在聚会上的书包
-Get it on the air in the next hour. -You got it.
-一小时内办好 -没问题
Fill that bag up with books and put it back.
往包里装进书，放回原处
Gonna eat this son of a bitch alive, knowing he missed this.
得活捉这个杂种 让他也知道漏了这点
You know something, Charlie? Maybe this isn't such a hot idea.
知道吗，查理？ 也许这么做并不明智
A guy picks up a bag, don't make him guilty.
就算有人来拿包 也不能证明他就是案犯
Will, it's solid.
威尔，证据很明显
I don't know. This kind of thing. Maybe we do this by the numbers.
我也不知道行不行 这套手法我们用的太多了
-Come on. -l.A.'s gonna be on my ass.
-行了 -内部调查科的人正紧盯着我
I don't want this turning up in some court when my rep's in the shit...
我不想这事转过头来被他们加以利用
-...and they're pulling apart my cases. -Bullshit.
-往我头上盖个胡乱办案的帽子 -别胡说了
What the fuck you care?!
你他妈在乎什么？！
Someone beat a girl to death. Your job is to find him.
有人将女孩殴打至死 你的任务就是将他找出来
You're a cop, not a lawyer. Don't let l.A. cut your balls off.
你是警察，不是律师 别让内部调查员限制了你的手脚
Charlie's right, Will.
查理说的对，威尔
OP 1, this is OP 2. We still got nothing.
一号监视点，这里是二号点 我们还没任何发现
Yeah, it's nice. Light.
是的，那很轻
All plastic except for the barrel. Never rusts.
除枪管外全为塑胶体，永不生锈
What do you carry down in L.A.?
你从洛杉矶带来的是什么？
-Smith & Wesson.45. -Excellent.
-史密斯点45口径 -很棒
-Anything? -No.
-有情况吗？ -没有
-Maybe he doesn't listen to the radio. -He prefers the voices in his head.
-也许他从不听收音机 -也许他是个妄想狂
Hey, Will?
威尔？
We have somebody moving towards the cabin.
有人向着小屋过来了
Okay, fan out. Nice and easy.
好，立即行动 注意保持隐蔽
Shit.
糟糕
Come on, go!
快上，快！
Police!
警察！
Police! Come out!
警察！快出来！
Fuck!
该死！
Down there, huh?
下去了吗？
Down to the water. Spread out!
他往水里跑了分头包抄！
Go!
快！
Fuck it.
见鬼去吧
Dormer!
多默！
Hold it! Who's there?
站住！谁在那儿？
-You okay? -I'm okay.
-你没事吧？ -没事
-Will? -Don't talk.
-威尔？ -别说话
-Will. -Don't talk. Don't talk.
-威尔 -别说话，别说
-Here. -You sh--
-等着 -你打--
You....
你…
You shot....
你射了…
I know. I couldn't see, Hap. I couldn't see in the fog.
我知道，我看不清楚 在雾里我什么也看不见
You tried to....
你想要…
You tried to kill me? Fuck you.
你想要杀我？去死吧
No, listen, Hap.
不，听着，哈普
-Listen to me now. No, no. -Get away, get away!
-听我说，别这样 -走开，走开！
No, I couldn't see you in the fog. I couldn't. I--
我没看清楚是你 我没办法--
I couldn't see you, Hap.
我没办法看清你，哈普
Don't go. Come on.
别死，坚持住
-Man down! -Who's down?
-有人中枪了！ -是谁？
-Man down here! -Spread out!
-这儿有人中枪了！ -快过去！
Dormer! Where'd he go? Which way?
多默！他往哪边走了？哪边？
Dormer! Which way?
多默！哪边？
That way.
那边
Fuck.
该死
You gave chase.
法雷尔中枪后，你继续追击
After you left Farrell, you heard the killer's second shot.
然后听到了凶手的第二次开枪
You ran down to the water. You found Hap.
你跑到水中，发现了哈普
Will?
威尔？
Is that what happened?
事情经过是这样的吗？
-Did Hap say anything? -Damn it!
-哈普有说什么吗？ -五八蛋！
Why didn't I know about the goddamn tunnel?
为什么没人告诉我还有地道？
You don't move on a suspect without knowing his exits.
不堵住逃跑路线怎么能抓住案犯
There's a bunch of those tunnels out there.
那儿的地道实在是太多了
Closed years ago when they were mines.
六十年前那里曾是矿坑 后来就被关闭了
-I don't even know most of them myself. -I had him, Charlie.
-就算是我也不清楚坑道的走向 -我本来就要逮到他了，查理
As close as you are now.
就象你现在般在我眼前
I could smell the son of a bitch.
我都能闻到那杂种身上的气味
-And I blew it. -There's no point in blaming yourself.
-可事情却被我搞砸了 -没必要这样责备你自己
-I fucked up everything. -Don't come apart on me, understand?
-我把一切都搞砸了 -别让我再分心了好吗？
I need you to find this bastard.
我需要你去找出这杂碎
Yeah.
过来
-You wanted to see me? -You're on Eckhart's shooting.
-你找我？ -你要处理艾克哈特被杀事宜
But we know what happened, and I'm on the Connell case.
可我们都知道发生了什么 而我正在负责康内尔案
Anchorage wants to send someone. I told them we can do it. Can't we?
安克雷奇要人过去汇报情况 我对他们说马上就派人去
-Sure. -Write it up. No Shakespeare.
-好的 -据实写报告，别虚构什么
Just enough to fry this son of a bitch longer. Right?
看来要留那杂种多逍遥几天了
Hello?
威尔？
Jenny, it's Will. Can you put your mother on?
珍尼，我是威尔 叫你妈接电话好吗？
Hello?
喂？
Trish, it's Will.
崔西，我是威尔
What's happened? They won't tell me anything.
出了什么事？他们什么也不肯说
It's Hap....
是哈普
Is he okay?
他还好吗？
No, he's gone, Trish.
不，他牺牲了，崔西
He' s dead.
他死了
What?
什么？
Trish, I can' t tell you how sorry I am.
崔西，我现在没办法说出自己的心情
What was he doing, Will?
他去干什么了，威尔？
This guy killed a girl, and, so we....
有个人杀了女孩，所以我们
We had him....
我们去抓那个人
We found him and we had him cornered. And then he ran and....
我们找到了他，包围了他 然后他企图逃跑
Hap....
而哈普…
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉
-I'm just so sorry. -Did he suffer?
-真的很抱歉 -他死的痛苦吗？
-No, I don't-- -Did he say anything?
-我不知道-- -他留下什么话吗？
Well, when I found him he....
当我找到他时….
He was peaceful.
他已经去了
-Did you get him? -No, no. Not yet.
-你抓到那凶手了吗？ -不，还没有
You find him.
你找到了凶手
And when you do, don 't arrest him.
但是却不上去逮捕他
You understand me, Will Dormer?
你该明白我的意思，威尔多默
Don't you dare fucking arrest him!
难道你没胆子逮捕他吗！
-Okay, Trish. - You understand?
-行了，崔西 -你知道吗？
Okay.
好了
Trish, listen.
崔西，听着
I' m--
我--
--was shot and killed this evening...
--于今晚在追踪本地 17岁少女被杀案的嫌疑犯时
...of 1 7-year-old local girl, Kay Connell.
被枪杀
I' m sorry. It' s been on the radio for hours.
很抱歉，收音机开着有一会了
We' re not used to this kind of stuff up here.
这儿不常发生这样的事
He was standing right there. Last night.
就在昨晚他还站过那儿
I hope I was nice to him.
真希望我能对他好些
He liked you.
他喜欢你
Detective? I'm sorry to bother you, but could you just point...
探长？很抱歉打搅你 可是你能指出…
...to where you were when you heard the second shot?
听到第二声枪声的地点吗？
Sorry to make you do this right now.
很抱歉现在让你做这事
That's all right. You're doing your job.
没关系，你也是在做自己的事
Where was l?
我在哪儿？
-There. -Thank you.
-在那儿 -谢谢
No sign of Farrell's bullet yet, huh?
射法雷尔的子弹找到了吗？
No, we'll have the other one for ballistics after...
还没有，只有从另一颗子弹上了解弹道
...the autopsy.
要等到尸解以后
I'm really sorry.
我很难过
-Clean through, huh? -Yeah.
-穿腿而过？ -是的
Bullet got lost in the rocks, I guess.
我想弹头该是掉在岩石间了
Well, better luck next time.
但愿下次运气好些
You ever been shot?
你中过枪吗？
Yeah, I have. Kind of itches, don't it?
是的，中过 伤口会很痒，不是吗？
We gotta catch him. Did you get a look at him?
我们得抓住他，你看清楚他样子了吗？
-When? -When I left you.
-什么时候？ -我离开你的时候
-You see anything? -I was in a lot of pain...
-你看到什么了吗？ -那时候我痛的受不了
...and when I heard that second shot, I kept my goddamn head down.
第二声枪响的时候，我没抬起头
Hey, I'm...
我…
...sorry about Detective Eckhart.
艾克哈特探员的事我很抱歉
Sorry about that megaphone.
还有扩音器的事
-Maybe if I hadn't-- -Farrell, listen.
-也许要是我没有-- -法雷尔，听着
What were we doing running around in the fog?
那时候我们为什么要在雾中奔跑？
We doing it for our health? We were chasing someone.
难道是在健身吗？ 我们是在追某个人
So anything that happened on that beach is not your fault.
所以海滩上发生的事并不是你的错
That's the fault of one man and one man only.
那儿只有一个人是错了
And that's the man who beat Kay Connell to death.
正是那个人杀死了凯康内尔
At this point, Dormer encountered Brooks.
就在这点上，多默遇到了布罗克
The suspect, obscured by fog, shot Officer Brooks...
而嫌疑犯隐匿在雾中 向布罗克警官开枪
...in the vastus externus of the left thigh.
子弹射中了左股
You're Farrell. You were shot in the leg.
你就是法雷尔，你的腿上中了枪
Come on, Ellie.
行了，埃莉
When you get this, get the cone.
中枪以后你就倒在了地上
-This his blood? -Ketchup maybe.
-这是他流的血吗？ -也许是番茄酱吧
Was he eating a hot dog?
好象那时候他是在吃热狗？
Anything he dropped...
找到他丢的东西…
...you put in a bag.
…就放进袋子里
Cigarette butts, gum wrappers, coins, anything.
烟头，口香糖包装纸，硬币 任何的东西
Suspect will often leave something behind.
案犯通常都会留下些东西
Detective Dormer...
多默探长…
...Iost the suspect in the fog then heard a shot...
在雾中追踪疑犯
...coming from a northeasterly direction.
然后听到东北方传来枪声
-He wasn't that way. -How do you know?
-不该是那样 -你怎么知道？
Because I saw him.
因为我看到他了
-Turn this way. -Are we almost done here?
-转过来些 -差不多了吧？
My nads are freezing off.
我的脖子就要冻僵了
Ellie! I think I found something.
埃莉！我找到什么了
-Should they start further over? -No.
-要他们从更远的地方开始吗？ -没必要
He stayed by the water far as he could.
他跳到水里拼命的跑
I saw him over the rocks. He knew he'd lose us down there.
然后我看到他越过那些岩石 他知道可以在那儿甩掉我们
Duggar.
我是杜格
Where'd he find it?
是在哪儿找到的？
Okay.
好的
Yeah, well, just let me know.
没关系，说吧
I will.
我会的
Dormer?
多默？
They found Farrell's bullet. Looks like a.38.
他们找到了射法雷尔的弹头 好象是点三八口径
We'll get both bullets to the lab.
现在就可以比较子弹了
See if we can get a fix on the weapon. If it's okay with you.
如果你觉得没问题 我们就开始推测案犯使用何种武器了
A guy came by. Said he was your new partner.
有人来找过你了 自称是你的新拍档
-Did he leave a name? -No.
-留下名字了吗？ -没有
Can I borrow this? Thank you.
能借用下吗？谢谢
-Pioneer Lodge. -Warfield for Dormer.
-先锋旅馆 -沃菲尔德找多默
John Warfield. He's called a couple times.
是约翰沃菲尔德 今天他来了好多电话
Want me to lie?
要我说你不在吗？
No, I'll take it.
不，我接
Thank you.
谢谢
Dormer here.
我是多默
I was shocked to hear about your partner. I was getting to know him--
听到你拍档的遭遇我深感震惊 我认识他还不久--
What do you want?
找我什么事？
You know what I want, Eckhart was gonna give it to me.
你知道是什么事 艾克哈特本来已经准备和我合作
You got something to say, just say it.
想说什么就直说
-He told you about our conversation? -Say it.
-他告诉你我们谈过了？ -说了
Let's just say I'm interested to see your report on what happened.
老实说我很有兴趣了解 你对此事的报告
Don't presume to know what happened.
不要凭空想象发生了什么
You weren' t here. But then, you never are, are you?
你不在案发现场 你也永远不会去那种地方，对吗？
You' re always safe behind some desk, reading your bullshit reports.
你只会躲在办公桌后面 看着什么狗屁报告
And that is why I have nothing but contempt for you.
所以我对你这人的看法 除了轻蔑就没别的了
You and all the assholes like you...
你和所有你那样的混蛋
...risk nothing, spend all day sucking the marrow out of real cops...
从不敢冒什么危险 只会整真正的警察
...when you never had the balls to be one yourself.
因为你们没胆量去做真正的警察
-Detective, you came yourself. -Yeah.
-探长，你是自己来的 -是
Sign here.
请在这儿签名
He didn't suffer too much.
他没有受太大的痛苦
-What's the caliber? -Don't know.
-是什么口径的子弹？ -不知道
The gunshot victims I see are from rifles. Wasn't one of those.
我只见过受来复枪击的受害人 这种子弹从没见过
-Had any sleep, detective? -Yeah.
-睡过了吗，探长？ -是的
-What the hell is wrong with you? -Sorry.
-你是怎么开车的？ -对不起
No problem.
没问题
-Bullet. I want results by tomorrow. -Aye, aye, cap'n.
-这是子弹，明天早上把报告给我 -好的
We should check Randy's whereabouts.
我们该去调查下兰迪的下落
Think it was Randy out there?
你认为那会是兰迪？
He still doesn't have an alibi. You said he beat Kay.
他还是没不在现场证明 你说过他打了凯
-You check it out, then. -I will.
-那就去查吧 -我会的
Detective Dormer?
多默探长？
My report. I finished.
我完成报告了
I need you to look it over and sign it.
看过后签个名好吗
It's self-explanatory. I look forward to getting back to work with you.
我也想尽快完成任务 然后继续跟着你破案
We have more important things to do than paperwork.
我们该做些比这类书面报告更重要的事
A man died, Ellie. This is important.
有人殉职了，埃莉 这才是最重要的
Of course. I didn't mean to imply that that wasn't--
当然，我的意思不是--
Be sure of your facts before you file this.
签名之前再核实下事实
It's your name on the report.
怎么可以先把名给签上去了
He couldn't have come from there.
他不可能从那儿过来
Dormer here.
我是多默
-Hello? -Can't sleep, Will?
-喂？ -睡不着吗？威尔
Me neither.
我也一样
Who' s this?
你是谁？
I got a nap this afternoon, but I guess you had to work.
下午我小睡了会 不过我想你还是得工作吧
Who am I speaking to?
你到底是谁？
Get rid of your clock yet? Won't help.
还没把生物钟调整过来？ 不会有用的
When I moved here, I went five nights. You believe that?
我刚到这儿时，也整整五晚没合眼
-This crazy light. -A name or l' m gonna hang up.
-这光线直教人发疯 -快说名字，不然我就挂了
No, you're not. You need the company. Nothing as lonely as not sleeping.
你不会挂的，你也在找伙伴 失眠的人最是寂寞
Feels like the whole fucking planet is deserted. Just you and me.
就感觉这该死的行星上荒无一人 只剩下你和我
So...
那么…
...tell me who l' m talking to, and we can chat a while.
告诉我你是谁 或许我们可以聊上那么会
-I can 't do that. -Why not?
-不行 -为什么？
-Not till you understand some things. -Like what?
-要在你明白些事以后才能告诉你 -比如什么？
I saw.
我全看到了
-Saw what? -Saw you shoot your partner.
-看到什么了？ -看到你杀了拍档
Saw him die in your arms on that beach.
看到他死在了你的怀里
I thought you'd blame me. That's why I dropped my gun.
我觉得你会因此迁怒于我 所以我扔掉了我的枪
-My uncle 's old.38. -Yeah.
-我叔叔的旧式点38手枪 -对
- You get it? What about ballistics? -Listen to me now.
-你明白了？子弹报告怎么说？ -现在听我说
I don' t know what you think you saw.
我不知道你自以为看到了什么
We should discuss this, don't you think? Face to face.
但我们或许可以谈谈 你觉得呢？面对面谈
This situation isn't yours to control. I saw you.
现在的局势不是你能控制的 我看到你杀了人
I'll control this situation, pal.
我会控制全盘局势，老兄
Because you don't hide from me in a town this small. Get it?
因为在这么小的镇子里 你无处可躲，明白吗？
No, not for long.
不，不再会了
I need your help. I'm not telling anyone anything.
我需要你的帮助 我也不会对别人说任何事
We're partners on this.
在这点上我们可以合作
--but to be remembered as the Kay we knew and loved.
--记得我们熟悉和深爱的凯吧
Swimming, hiking through the Kebaughs...
活泼好动，热爱生活
...meeting at Darrow' s after school...
在校园里也勤奋好学
...and always, always with a smile on her face.
脸上永远都洋溢着微笑
Detective Dormer?
多默探长？
I want to check something. I was going over my report last night...
我想再核实点事实 昨晚我又仔细看了遍报告
...and I have a question about where that second shot came from.
我对第二次枪击的来源有点疑问
You said you heard it from the waterline...
你说你听到枪声是从水边传来的
...but from the way Detective Eckhart's body fell...
但是从艾克哈特探长倒下的角度
...it couldn't have come from the rocks further up from the water.
子弹不可能是由 远离水域的岩石上射过来
Do you think it's possible you heard the shot before you hit the waterline?
在到达水边之前你可能听到枪声吗？
-Detective Dormer? -Yeah, it's possible.
-多默探长？ -是的，可能
Yeah.
是的
Why don't I give her a ride?
我能载她一程吗？
-Thought I smelled something. -How you doing? Coping?
-我就想这臭味是哪儿传来的 -最近怎么样？还是抬不起头来？
-You're that cop. -Yeah.
-你就是那个警察 -是的
-Are you coming or not? -Not.
-跟不跟我走？ -不
You want a stick of gum? I love chewing gum.
要来片口香糖吗？ 我很喜欢嚼口香糖
It keeps me awake.
能让我保持清醒
-I never met anyone from L.A. before. -Not missing much.
-我从未见过洛杉矶来的人 -没什么大不了的
-So how do you like our shithole town? -It's not bad.
-觉得我们的破镇子怎么样？ -还不赖
-Were you good friends with Kay? -Best friends. Since grade school.
-你和凯是好朋友？ -是最亲密的朋友，小学起就在一起了
-That's a long time. -Yeah, we were like sisters.
-那可不短了 -是的，我们亲如姐妹
Like sisters? Must be tough for you what happened, then.
亲如姐妹？那这事对你打击一定很大
Everyone keeps telling me I'm doing great, considering.
所有人都说我做的很好
But they're all real worried about me.
可是他们只会让我更烦
They don't even care if I show up for school or not.
他们不在乎我会不会在学校里出现
Worried I haven't cried yet.
却只在乎我会不会在葬礼上哭
But ain't no law says you gotta cry, right?
但没法律规定必须要哭，对吗？
No, there ain't.
是没有
What about her other friends?
那她其他的朋友们呢？
Do we have to talk about Kay right now? God.
我们现在非得说凯的事吗？
I don't want to think about all that. Just drive.
我不想再想这些事 就带我兜兜风吧
I understand.
明白了
-Want me to take you somewhere? -As long as it's fun.
-要我带你去什么地方？ -只要是有趣的地方就行
Young, impressionable girl...
年轻，多情的女孩
...Ieft alone with older Los Angeles cop. Who knows where we might go?
跟洛杉矶来的年长警察单独相处 谁知道我们会做出什么来？
Well, I know a place.
行，我知道有个好地方
Let's just drift a while.
让我们来放松下
Look at this.
看看这个
Who does he think he is?
他以为他是谁？
What does he think he's doing?
他以为自己在干什么？
-Move over. -Let him move over.
-快避开 -叫他让我们
Come on! Move over!
快！避开！
What are you doing? Move over, you crazy fuck!
你在干什么？你这个疯子！
Just a little visit to the dump!
带你来见下垃圾场！
-You should feel at home. -You just about killed us! Get off me!
-你会感觉亲切如家 -你刚差点让我们没命！放开我！
-What is this? -You and Kay were like sisters?
-到这里来干什么？ -你和凯亲如姐妹？
-Yes. I told you. -Why are her pictures of you torn?
-对，我已经跟你或了 -那为什么她要撕去跟你的合照？
Why was her boyfriend's hands all over your ass at her funeral?
为什么她的男朋友会在葬礼上缠着你？
Randy doesn't have an alibi because he was with you.
兰迪不说出不在场证明 是因为他当时在和你鬼混
You were out fucking your best friend's boyfriend.
你居然和你最要好朋友的男朋友鬼混
-That what best friends do? -She never really loved Randy, okay?
-那就算是最好的朋友吗？ -她从未真正爱过兰迪，明白？
-She didn't love him? -No.
-她不爱他？ -是的
How do you figure that? She have someone else?
什么意思？她有了别的人？
-I don't know. -Someone bought her dresses, jewelry?
-我不知道 -有人给她买了衣服和首饰？
Hey, look around.
过来瞧瞧
I want to show you something. You'll understand why I brought you.
我来给你看些东西 你会明白我为什么带你来这里
This is the spot where your best friend's naked body was dumped.
你最要好朋友的裸尸 就是被遗弃在这里
Wrapped up in garbage bags!
被塞在垃圾袋里！
Tanya...
塔尼娅
...I know you don't want anyone knowing you betrayed your best friend.
我知道你不想任何人知道 你背叛了你的好朋友
That's why you won't give Randy an alibi for Friday night. I know.
所以你不愿给兰迪做不在场证明
Tell me who Kay was seeing. And we can forget the whole thing.
告诉我凯去找谁了 那么这件事我们就此不提
It'd be our secret. Our little secret, but I need a name.
就当是我们的秘密 不过我要你告诉我那人的名字
She wouldn't tell me, okay?
她没告诉过我，行了吧？
She wouldn't tell you? You're her best friend.
她没对你说过？ 你们可是最亲密的朋友
-lt was her big fucking secret! -Why a secret?
-那是她的大秘密！ -为什么要保密？
I don't-- Because she thought she was special...
我不知道-- 因为她总觉得自己很了不起
...and she kept saying he'd help her get out of here.
她老是说他能帮她离开这里
-Who is "he"? -I don't know.
-那个“他”是谁？ -我不知道
-She talked about him? -Yeah.
-她说过他的事？ -是的
-She talked to you?
-是对你说的吗？
And what did she call him?
那她是怎么称呼他的？
-She called him something, right? -Yes!
-她总得给他个名字吧？ -是的！
What? What'd she call him?
是什么？她是怎么称呼他的？
Brody.
布罗迪
She called him Brody. That's not his name, so what's the difference?
她就叫他布罗迪，但那不是他的真名 知道了又有什么用？
Jesus! You happy now, you fucking asshole?
现在你满意了？ 你这个该死的混蛋！
Okay. You did good. Come on. I'll let you drive.
你做的很好，来吧 我这就送你回去
It's just poetry. I read it line by line.
只是很普通的诗集 里面的每字每句我都读过了
It's nothing specific. Verses on nature, love. That sort of stuff.
没什么特别的 都是些关于自然，爱情的诗
Detective Dormer. Line one.
多默探长，一号线有人找
-Dormer here. -How're you holding up?
-我是多默 -现在感觉如何？
Can't be easy to keep working after three days of no sleep.
三个不眠之夜后 要继续工作该会困难
And hard to keep focus.
而且很难集中注意力
Are you seeing things yet?
还在找线索吗？
You know, those little flashes? Tricks of light?
想要灵机一动找到破案关键？
See your partner?
看见你的拍档了吗？
-I see Kay sometimes. -What can I do for you, sir?
-我也经常会见到凯 -我能为你做些什么，先生？
Why couldn 't you tell anyone you shot him?
为什么不向别人坦白是你开的枪？
I mean, it was an accident, right?
我是说，这不过是个意外对吗？
I hope so. For your sake. You know what I'm saying?
我也希望是，那是为了你好 你该清楚我在说什么吧？
No need for threats.
没必要恐吓我
I'm trying to make you understand my situation.
我只是想让你明白我的处境
You thought no one would believe you because of the trouble in L.A.
你认为由于你在洛杉矶的麻烦 没有人会相信你
I know what that's like, Will.
我明白那种感受，威尔
-I got the same problem. -You do?
-我也面临同样的问题 -是吗？
I'm not who you think I am.
我并不是你所想的那种人
-You' re not? -No.
-你不是？ -不是
-I'm not a murderer any more than you. -Why don' t we get together?
-我和你一样都不能算是凶手 -为什么我们不能见个面？
-T al k, have a beer, whatever? -Throw a little gas on the fire?
-聊聊天，喝杯啤酒什么的？ -想要火上浇油吗？
Yeah--
是的--
I gotta go check some things. Why don' t you...
我要出去查些事 你能不能…
...put this stuff back into evidence and tell....
将这些物件放回证物间 然后再告诉…
-What' s that guy? -Fred.
-那家伙叫什么来着？ -佛瑞德
T ell him l' ll see him in the morning.
告诉他明天早上我要见他
Can we return this? Her mother might like it.
我们可以把这交还她的家人吗？ 她母亲也许会高兴点
Sure.
当然
That's right.
乖，过来
Here.
给你们
This is Walter. Leave a message, wait for the beep.
我是沃尔特，请在嘟声后留言
Will, you there? Where else can you go in that state?
威尔，你在听吗？ 这个状态下，你该也没别处可去
You must've been freezing.
你一定冻的够呛
If you want, take a shower. There are clean towels in the bathroom.
若是愿意，就去冲个澡吧 浴室里有干净的毛巾
This is Walter. Leave a message, wait for the beep.
我是沃尔特，请在嘟声后留言
Will, pick up. I'm not dumb enough to come back--
威尔，把电话拿起来 我不想像这样子自言自语--
-Walter Finch. - Will.
-沃尔特芬奇 -威尔
Will Dormer, what are you doing?
威尔多默，你来这儿干什么？
I try to help and you're running around like a maniac.
我只想要帮你 而你却象是疯子般的到处追我
Were you gonna kill me? How would you explain that?
你是不是想要杀我？ 这事你要怎么解释？
No one gets too upset when child murderers are brought in feet first.
看到拔腿就跑的谋杀犯 谁都是会那样反应
There's no evidence I killed Kay. You know because I told you.
又没有证据表明是我杀了凯 你知道也只是因为我这么对你说
-Come on. What's wrong with you? -Guess I'm a little cranky.
-行了，你到到底是怎么了？ -可能我是有些暴燥
-Lack of sleep. -Get some rest, will you?
-是因为缺乏睡眠吧 -那就好好休息
Got some pills, and my bed's nice and comfy.
含上点药片睡一觉 我的床还是很舒服的
Another night up and you'll lose it. Hallucinating, babbling.
再有一晚上不休息你就会失控了 会产生幻觉，开始胡言乱语
Tomorrow when you feel better, we 'll meet in public. We 'll sort it out.
明天你要是觉得舒服些了 我们就在公众场合见个面
There 's a ferry north of Nightmute. I'll be on the 1 1 :00.
寂夜镇的北边有个渡口 我们11点在那里见
And before you leave, could you feed the dogs? They're on a diet.
你在走之前能不能帮我喂喂狗？ 它们不怎么挑食
Dormer? Fax from the lab.
多默？子弹报告出来了
Weapon was a.38 Smith & Wesson.
凶枪的型号是史密斯点38口径
-We found something that might-- -I found this. At the Connells'.
-我们还发现有些-- -我在康内尔家找到的这个
And?
怎么？
It's the author of the book we found in Kay's bag.
这就是我们在凯的包里 发现的那本书的作者
It's signed by the author. He's a local.
这是作者的签名，他是本地人
Kay had all his books. We should check it out.
凯有他所有的书，我们该去查查
-Small stuff, right? -Yeah. Sure, sure.
-从小处着手，对吗？ -是的，没错
Nice work, Ellie. She's got sharp eyes, huh?
干的漂亮，埃莉 她的眼睛真的很尖
You bet your ass she does.
她当然是
Good stuff.
很不错
What a view.
风景不错
-I'm not who you think I am. -No?
-我不是你想象中的那种人 -不是？
Walter Finch:
沃尔特芬奇
Lousy writer. Lonely freak.
落魄作家，独居怪胎
Murderer. No?
杀人凶手，不是吗？
When I was 7, my grandmother took me to Portland.
我还是七岁时，我祖母带我去了波特兰
We were walking along and two guys snatched her purse.
我们在外面散步时 有两个家伙抢了她的钱包
A police officer came to ask questions.
后来有位警官来酒店做询问
He stood the whole time. Uniform looked brand-new.
他一直都站着 穿着崭新的制服
Shoes, badge were polished. It was like a soldier, only better.
皮鞋，警徽都被擦的闪亮 就象是战士，比战士还要威武
I respect your profession. I write about it.
我很敬重你的职业 我在作品里就写到过
I wanted to become a cop after school. I couldn't pass all the tests.
学校毕业我就想做警察 可是测试却不合格
You should've tried lnternal Affairs. They'd have taken you.
你该试试去内部调查科报名 他们应该会录取你
What do you want from me?
你想从我这儿得到什么？
After Kay died, I knew everyone would think I meant to do it.
凯死后，我知道所有人 都会认为我是有意的
So I cleaned the body, removed all evidence connecting it to me.
所以我清理了尸体 消除了所有对我不利的证据
Except for your fucking novel.
除了你那本该死的书
You don't always see the wood for the trees.
在重压之下 谁也不能将事情做的面面俱到
You, for one, should have figured that out by now.
你现在就该很有体会了
When I heard they had brought somebody from L.A., I panicked.
当听说他们从洛杉矶派人来时 我就有些害怕
I knew the locals would connect me to Kay eventually.
我清楚本地的警察不会查到我的头上
I could handle them. They never look in the eyes of a killer.
我能应付他们 他们看不穿凶手的心思
Killing changes you. You know that.
杀人能使你改变，你该也清楚
It's not guilt.
那不算是犯罪
I never meant to do it.
我并不是有意这么做的
It's like awareness.
就象是潜意识里有感觉
Life is so important. How could it be so fucking fragile?
生命是如此重要 怎么可能会这般脆弱？
You'd see it right away, wouldn't you?
你也该有同样的感受吧？
You trying to impress me? Because you got the wrong guy.
还想唬我？那你就找错人了
Killing that girl made you feel special.
杀了那女孩让你感觉很特殊
But you're not.
可是你错了
You're the same pathetic freak I've been dealing with for 30 years.
你就和我过去三十年来 所对付的可悲杂碎们一样
Know how many of you I caught with your pants down?
知道我逮了多少象你这样的家伙吗？
-I never touched her like that. -You wanted to. Now you wish you had.
-我从未碰过她 -但是你想碰，还在后悔没捞到手吧
Best you could do is clip her nails.
你干的最漂亮的 就是剪去了她的指甲
Now you're so different. You don't get it, do you?
现在你就真的不同了 你不太明白我说的？
You're my job. You're what I'm paid to do.
逮捕你是我的工作 我拿钱就是抓你这种人
You're about as mysterious to me as a toilet is to a plumber.
我对你的兴趣 就好比水管工对厕所有兴趣一样
Reasons for doing what you did? Who gives a fuck?
谁他妈在乎你作案的动机？
Motivations are everything, Will.
什么都可能成为动机，威尔
What did you see through the fog?
透过雾你看到了什么？
I saw pretty clearly, didn't l? I saw you take aim...
当时我看的很清楚 我看到你举枪瞄准
-Forget it. -...shoot your partner in the chest.
-行了 -往你的拍档胸前开枪
I heard him say, "Get away from me!" Why?
我听到他说“别碰我！” 为什么？
Anything to do with lnternal Affairs investigation?
是因为内部调查的缘故？
All that tension in your department?
那让你紧张过度了？
-You think I'm that easy? -I'm saying that's how it looks.
-你以为我会那么简单？ -我只是说事情看起来就象
Maybe even how it feels.
或许是感觉起来吧
How did it feel when you found out it was Hap? Guilt? Relief?
知道射中的是哈普时是什么感觉？ 内疚？解脱？
Suddenly, you're free and clear. Did you think about it before that moment?
忽然间，你就不再会受牵连了 这之前你有想过这么做吗？
What would it be like if he wasn't there anymore?
或是想若没他这个人情况会是如何？
Doesn't mean you did it on purpose.
并不是说你这么去做就是有动机的了
You figure if you got something on me, then I'll just roll over?
你以为抓住了我的把柄 我就会屈服了？
-Protect my reputation? -No.
-为了保护我的声誉？ -错了
Protect your life's work.
是为了保护你这辈子的工作
The scumbags you put away will be back on the street before you go on trial.
那些被关进去的垃圾们 不用等到你被审判就会被放出来
With Hap gone, you're free and clear. Why mess with that?
哈普死了你就免去了麻烦 那样有什么不好的？
Kay Connell. Remember her?
那凯康内尔呢？你忘了她了？
It's your choice.
这就要看你的选择了
Think of all the other Kay Connells.
想想所有的凯康内尔们吧
Do the math. You're a pragmatist. You have to be because of your job.
做道算术题，你是个实际的人 因为工作你必须如此
This isn't easy, but I want you to understand...
虽然这很难，但我希望你能明白
...we're in the same situation here.
我们的处境是相同的
You didn't mean to kill Hap any more than I meant to kill Kay.
你并不想杀哈普 而我也不是有意杀死凯
But that's hard for them to believe, so that's why we need each other.
但是别人就很难相信 因此我们才互相需要
We gotta find a patsy for the Connell case and make it stick.
要把康内尔的案子了结 就要找个替死鬼
Then you go back to Los Angeles and I can go back to living my life.
然后你就回洛杉矶 而我也继续过我的生活
So, what do you need from me?
那你要我做点什么？
What do they know about me?
他们对我了解有多少？
They found a signed copy of one of your books at Kay's house.
他们在凯的家找到了你签过名的书
-So you'll be brought in for questioning. -At the station?
-所以你会被叫去问话 -去警局？
That's what they usually do.
他们通常都这么做
Brought in for questioning. I can write that easily.
被叫去问话，我都可以写进小说了
Calm down. It's no big thing. It's preliminary inquiry, so...
冷静，没什么大不了的 这不过是例行调查，所以
...just tell the truth.
说实话就行
-Tell them about Randy-- -Why are you talking about Randy?
-跟他们说兰迪-- -为什么要提起兰迪？
Talk about your relationship with Kay. You can't hide it, so just say it.
跟他们说你和凯的关系 这是没办法隐瞒的，所以就说
Randy is none of your business. It's not your affair.
兰迪不关你的事，你不用多操心
Shouldn't I tell them she was unhappy--
那我是不是该告诉他们 她最近很不开心--
Tell them she was unhappy, but let them find Randy themselves.
告诉他们她不开心， 但是让他们自己把兰迪挖出来
That way, they'll make it stick.
那样做，他们才会相信是真的
Understand?
明白吗？
We need a wild card.
我们还需要张五牌
-A wild card? -Yeah. Something that's there.
-五牌？ -对，已经发生的某些事
Something we can use. It's in every good detective novel.
某些我们可以利用的东西 每本优秀侦探小说都有写
You still have the.38?
那只点38还在你手上吗？
No.
不在
Really? That's a shame.
真的？那就麻烦了
We could use that. That'd be very convincing for them.
我们本来可以利用那个的 那样就更有信服力了
This is my stop.
我要在这下了
Dormer!
多默！
Wild card!
五牌！
-Night, everyone. -Night, Francis.
-各位晚安 -晚安，弗朗西斯
Working some overtime?
还要超时加班吗？
-Nice. -Cracking some big cases?
-真漂亮 -在破大案子？
-Night. -Night, guys.
-晚安 -各位晚安
This is always the worst time of night for me.
每到晚上我就觉得不好受
Too late for yesterday, too early for tomorrow.
想改变昨天的已经太晚 要开始明天的又太早
Sorry about the tape. I had to make sure you'd follow through.
录音带的事情真是很抱歉 我得确定你是不是真想合作
I'll follow through.
我会合作
I've been thinking it over. I should tell them about Randy.
我仔细考虑过了 我还是该和他们说兰迪的事
-I think that's a bad idea. -But he's the patsy. He deserves it.
-我觉得这主意不好 -因为他就该做替死鬼
You should have heard the shit Kay told me.
你该听听那个凯是怎么对我说的
But these are cops. They're not children.
那些都是警察，不是三岁小孩
You don't throw things like that in their lap.
你没必要那事实推到他们面前 去叫他们相信
I'll push them toward Randy.
我会让他们把目标转向兰迪
When the time is right.
只要时机合适
We don't have the gun. How will we convince them he's guilty?
我们没有那只枪 怎样才能叫他们相信他是凶手？
Did you keep the dress?
你留下了那件外套吗？
The dress?
外套？
Kay's dress, nail clippings. What did you do with those?
凯的外套，还有被剪下的指甲 你是怎么处理了？
That's great. The dress. We could use that. Even better than the gun.
是的，那件外套我们能派上用场 效果可能比那枪还好
-Where could he have taken her? -Where'd you take her?
-他会把她带去哪儿？ -你带她去了哪儿？
-She died in the cabin, right? -Yeah.
-她死在了那间小屋里对吗？ -是的
Where'd you take her to clean her up?
你是去哪里把她清理干净的？
Don't think about that. This is tough enough for you.
别去管那个 你不明白这个的
-lt was an accident. -Yeah.
-那不过是意外 -是的
-I didn't mean to kill her, you know. -I know, but what happened?
-你知道，我并非有意杀她 -我明白，但到底是怎么回事？
She called and said that she and Randy had had a fight.
她给我来了电话 说她和兰迪大吵一架
She wanted to come over and talk, and I said, " Meet me at our place."
她想过来和我聊聊 于是我说，“就在老地方见”
That's the cabin at the beach.
就是海滩上的那间小屋
She comes over. She's distraught and a little drunk.
她去了，而且有点酒喝过了头
She starts telling me about how Randy and Tanya were carrying on.
她开始说兰迪和坦尼娅是怎么交往的
I only wanted to comfort her. Hold her.
我只想让她好受些 我抱了她
I kissed her, and got a little excited...
还吻了她，可能有些过于激动
...and she started laughing at me.
于是她就开始嘲笑我了
She wouldn't stop laughing.
她不停的笑
Ever had someone laugh at you when you're like that? Vulnerable.
那样的情况下若有人也这么耻笑你 你会怎么做？
Laughing their ass off? Someone you thought respected you?
难道让他们笑？ 况且你还认为她很尊敬你
You ever have that happen?
你碰到过这样的事吗？
I just wanted to stop her laughing. And then, you know...
我只想叫他别笑 然后就，你知道…
...I hit her.
我打了她
Couple of times, to stop her. Get a little respect.
只是一两下，只是为了叫她别笑 想靠那得回对我的敬重
Randy did it all the time. She liked it when he did it.
兰迪不也总是打她吗？ 他打的时候怎么她就很愿意？
She never blamed him. Never wanted to leave him.
她也不会反抗他 因为她不想离开他
I do it, she starts screaming. She wouldn 't stop.
而我这么做的时候，她就开始大叫 怎么也不肯闭嘴
She' s screaming. I put my hand over her mouth.
她就这么喊着 我只好用手捂住她的嘴
Then l' m really scared. I' m scared shitless.
然后我就真的怕了，我怕极了
More scared than l' ve ever been. I' m more scared than her.
从没有这么害怕过 甚至比她还要恐惧
And then...
然后…
...everything was clear.
一切就都发生了
There was no turning back.
做出的事已经无可挽回
And after that, I was calm.
再后来，我就冷静下来了
Real calm.
非常冷静
You and I share a secret.
你和我共有一个秘密
We know how easy it is to kill somebody.
我们都知道杀死一个人是多么简单
That ultimate taboo. It doesn't exist outside our minds.
那种最根本的禁忌 并不存在于我们的意识之外
I didn't murder her.
我没有谋杀她
I killed her, but it just ended up that way.
虽然她死了 但是事情本来就是那样收场的
So where'd you take the body?
那你把尸体带去哪儿了？
Thanks for listening to me.
谢谢你能听我说
Feels good to talk about that stuff. I'll be able to sleep now.
把憋在心的话说出来真好 现在我能睡着了
You wanna talk about Hap?
你想说说哈普的事吗？
-Morning. -Your phone isn't working.
-早上好 -打你的电话总没人接
I turned it off. I needed to sleep. Sorry.
我拔了电话线 我想好好睡上觉
Fred called that author. He was happy to cooperate.
佛瑞德给那作家打了电话 他很愿意合作
He'll be in first thing, so we need to get to the office.
他说一早就过来， 所以我们得尽快去办公室
I forgot to tell you they sell these in stores in Anchorage.
忘记告诉你了 这在安克雷奇的商店里都有卖
-No way of finding out who bought it. -Okay.
-所以没办法知道是谁买的 -好的
Bet you're looking forward to getting back to L.A.
可能你打算回洛杉矶去了吧
Back to robbery homicide, or...
回凶杀组工作，或是…
...maybe not.
…也许不会
-What are you saying to me, Ellie? -Nothing.
-你想说什么，埃莉？ -没什么
Are you doing okay? You haven't been sleeping much.
你还习惯这里吗？ 看起来睡的并不久
No, I haven't. No.
不，我睡的很好
A good cop can't sleep because a piece of the puzzle's missing.
好警察无法入睡 是因为寻求不到破案的关键
A bad cop, because his conscience won't let him.
而坏警察，则是因为受到良心的折磨
-You said that once. -I did?
-这是你说过的 -我说的？
Sounds like something I'd say, don't it?
听起来是挺象我说过的
I'll see you back there.
警局见
In what regard were you and her familiar?
你和她是什么关系？
-How did you know her? -She was an avid reader of my novels.
-你是怎么认识她的？ -她是我的热心读者
When did you meet her first?
最早你们是怎么相遇的？
A year ago. She came to a signing in Nightmute.
一年以前，她参加了 我在寂夜镇的签名活动
She hung around afterwards. We chatted about my writing...
之后她并没有走 我们聊起了我的作品
...and how she wanted to write...
还说起了她也很想写作
...then she asked if she could visit me and talk about books, things like that.
问我是不是能来找我谈些关于书的事
-And she did? -Yeah, we became very close.
-后来她来找你了？ -是的，我们也就亲密起来
She got comfortable enough to show me her writing.
她很愿意给我看她的作品
-What does she write? -Poetry, actually.
-她都写些什么？ -都只是些诗
-Any good? -No, not really.
-写的好吗？ -不怎么样，都一般
-You tell her that? -Why would l?
-你跟她说了没有？ -我为什么要说？
Exactly what was the nature of your relationship to this girl, Finch?
你和这女孩的关系就那么单纯，芬奇？
I was someone she could talk to. Someone outside of her everyday life.
我只是个她能谈心的人 远离她日常生活之外的人
That's why she needed me and approached me.
所以她才会需要我，靠近我
Why'd she need you for that?
她为什么需要你？
-Well, her boyfriend, Randy-- -Randy Stetz?
-因为她男朋友兰迪-- -兰迪史特兹？
-Abusive little prick. He hit her. -We know all this already.
-那个小五八蛋，他总是打她 -这情况我们早就知道
-lt was getting worse. -So?
-这情况后来愈演愈烈 -怎样？
A lot worse. Really.
肯定会到不可收拾的地步
Why all this eagerness to talk about Randy?
为什么你对兰迪那么热心？
You're right. I'm sorry. That's probably all hearsay.
你说的对，我很抱歉 那些话并没有什么根据
I don't want anything I say taken the wrong way.
我可不想说错了话误导别人
Anything you say to us at this stage is in confidence.
你在这儿所说的一切都会被保密
Secondly, we're not a bunch of hotheads who'll draw crazy conclusions.
其次，我们也都有自己的判断力
-Okay. -Please, continue.
-好的 -请继续
One more thing. Probably doesn't mean much, but I think Kay was scared.
还有件事，也许并不代表什么 可我觉得凯受到了恐吓
-I have myself to blame for that. -Why is that?
-为此我也深受自责 -什么？
Randy knew who I was. He knew that she had a friend...
兰迪知道我是谁 他知道她交了个朋友
...someone she confided in. It made him furious.
某个她可以信赖的人 这让他很生气
She wrote about being scared. Her letters were getting desperate.
她写了关于受恐吓的事 她的信里充满了绝望
You still have these letters, by any chance?
你是不是还留有那些信？
I probably do. Do you think it might help?
应该还留着，这对此案有用吗？
They might.
会有用的
Okay. Anything else?
还有什么情况？
The thing that worried her the most was the gun.
她最担心的是那把枪
He had this old handgun. He showed it to her.
他有把旧手枪，他给她看过
I don't know where he got it, probably wasn't even his...
我不知道他是那儿搞来的 或许并不是他自己的
...but he said he'd use it if he found out who she was seeing.
但他扬言若找到她在和谁交往 就会用上这把枪
He kept it hidden in a heating vent. You know, in the skirting boards?
他把枪藏在暖气口里 可能就是那种地板上的通风口吧？
It might be the.38.
可能是把点38手枪
-Get me Judge Biggs. -What?
-给我接比格斯法官 -你干什么？
I'm getting a search warrant to Randy's.
我要申请搜查令去搜查兰迪的家
-Get Judge Biggs on the phone. -I should get over there.
-接比格斯法官 -我得去趟那儿
-No! -No?
-不！ -不？
You're the guy he's talking to. So we're waiting for the warrant. Okay?
既然都是你在审了 那我们就不如等搜查令好了
Do you know when Randy showed her the gun?
兰迪是什么时候给她看的枪？
February?
二月？
No, probably January.
不，好象是一月
Why didn't you come forward when she died?
她死后你为什么并未出现？
-She didn't want anybody to know. -Even when she was dead?
-她不想别人知道我们的关系 -即使是她死后？
Beaten to death. Her body dumped on a pile of garbage!
被殴至死，尸体被遗弃到垃圾场里！
-I was her friend. -No!
-我是她的朋友 -不是！
-Acquaintance. We were close-- -Close?
-是熟人，我们很亲密-- -亲密？
She was attractive. Did you have sex with her?
她是那么迷人 你有想和她做爱吗？
-She was 1 7. -Seventeen? She was attractive.
-她才17岁 -17岁？她可是很漂亮啊
I suppose.
可能吧
Suppose? She was. So did you have sex with her?
可能？她就是 那么你和她上过床了？
-No, I was her mentor. -You bought her things. Gifts.
-不，我是她的导师 -你给她买过东西吗？比如礼物？
-Yes. -What kind of gifts?
-是的 -是怎样的礼物？
-Books, mostly, that's what she loved. -Books? What about this?
-基本上都是些她喜欢的书 -书？那这个呢？
-You give her this? -Yes.
-这是你买的吗？ -是的
Why?
为什么？
-To see how she looked with it on? -No.
-想看她戴上后会是什么样子？ -不
-No? Why jewelry? -lt was just a present.
-不？那买首饰干什么？ -这只是件礼物
-Bought a lot of presents? Dresses? -What's wrong with that?
-会买那么多的礼物？衣服呢？ -那又怎么了？
Nothing. I'm figuring out what kind of mentor you were.
没什么，我在想你算是哪门子导师
I gave her things she couldn't have.
我只是给她些她没有的东西
You wanted to fuck her, didn't you? Sick son of a bitch!
你想要和她上床，对吗？ 你这肮脏的杂种！
-Cool off. -Sick bastard.
-别冲动 -肮脏的混蛋
You have to cool down. Okay? Cool down.
你得冷静，好吗？冷静
All right. I need a break.
好吧，我休息会
I have to apologize on behalf of my colleague.
我得为我同事的言行道歉
He's been under a lot of pressure lately. But he's a good cop.
近来他的压力很大 但他是个好警察
I'd hate to see the bad cop.
我也讨厌见到坏警察
Search and seizure warrant. Yes, sir.
申请搜查令 是的，先生
Randy Stetz.
兰迪史特兹
-We got our warrant! -Thank you. We appreciate it.
-搜查令拿到了！ -多谢合作，我们不胜感激
Francis, come with me. Let's go!
弗朗西斯，跟我来 我们走！
-You're not going? -No.
-你不一起去吗？ -不
Are you not on the Connell case?
你不负责康内尔案？
I'm covering the shooting of Detective Dormer's partner.
我在调查多默探长的拍档被枪杀案
Heard about that.
听说了
-Should I call about Kay's letters? -Yeah. I'll pick them up.
-还需要凯的信件吗？ -是的，我会去取
Stetz! We're coming in!
史特兹！我们要进来了！
Turn the place over.
搜这个地方
Look there! Try over there!
查查那边！去那里找！
Rich, look here now.
里奇，你查这儿
I got it! Hey, Fred!
我找到了！佛瑞德！
-Just in time, Dormer. -Had it in the motor oil.
-来的真及时，多默 -在机油里找到的
What the fuck is this?
这是怎么回事？
He says he was with Tanya when Kay was killed.
他说凯被杀时 他和坦尼娅在一起
-That's what she told me. -When?
-她也是这么对我说的 -什么时候？
-When I questioned her. -Were you planning on telling us?
-我问她的时候 -怎么没和我们说？
That's what I'm doing now.
我现在不就说了
Randy and Tanya were screwing around. She's trying to protect him.
兰迪和坦尼娅早就搭在一起 她会找借口给他开脱
-And the gun? -Says it isn't his.
-那这枪呢？ -据说不是他的
If we get the ballistics match, he'll be forthcoming.
若是证明子弹吻合 那他就将被定罪
-Leaving? -First thing tomorrow.
-打算走了吗？ -明天一早就可以走
If Spencer can remember where he parked the plane.
只要斯宾塞还记得他把飞机停在哪里了
I thought you wanted to kill me in the interview room.
我还以为在审讯室里你想杀了我
-Randy is in jail. -Said I'd write an ending they'd like.
-兰迪被关进去了 -看来我写了个他们喜欢的结尾
You were wrapped up in details.
你太在乎这些小事了
-The details? He's innocent. -No, he isn't.
-小事？他可是无辜的 -不，他不无辜
He beat Kay. One day he'd do something worse.
他打了凯，总有天他会做出更恶劣的事
You knew I planted the gun?
你怎么知道我放了那枪？
You wanted to help me before the tape recorder.
因为你在被录那卷带子前就已经想帮我了
You had to have a wild card.
你必须得有张五牌
You're a good man. I know that, even if you've forgotten it.
你是个好人，我很清楚 即使你自己都不记得了
When were you gonna point them at me? When you found Kay's dress?
打算什么时候带他们来找我？ 什么时候你会找到凯的外套？
Where I took the body? If you have a gun and forensics...
我曾把尸体带到哪儿去了？ 若是让你带人在我这儿找到枪
...wouldn't matter what I said about you killing your partner.
那不管我怎么说你拍档是怎么死的 也不会有人信了
May I have the tape?
录音带能给我吗？
-Did you make any other copies? -Why would l?
-有复制其他的带子吗？ -我为什么要这么做？
Stop me from turning you in.
让我不再能把你关进去
Or killing you.
或是杀了你
I don't have a hold over you. You made choices.
我没有逼你，是你自己做的选择
Like I wasn't here. Why kill me? It won't help Randy.
本来就没我的事，为什么要杀我？ 这也帮不了兰迪
After your scene at the department, it won't do you good if I'm dead.
而且就局里你对我的态度 杀了我对你也没好处
-A lot of ways a man can die. -Like an accident? Like Hap.
-人可以有很多种死法 -比如说意外？就象哈普那样
Like Kay.
象凯那样
It took you 1 0 minutes to beat Kay Connell to death.
你花了足足十分钟时间打死了凯
Ten fucking minutes. You calling that an accident?
足足十分钟！ 你怎么能说那是意外？
It took you a fraction of a second to kill your partner.
不到一秒的时间你就杀了拍档
Is that more of an accident?
那不也是意外？
Is this an accident?
那你说这会算是意外吗？
If you want it to be.
若是你想就是了
It's over, Walt.
该结束了，沃尔特
It's over. I'm telling them everything. Tell them about Hap, you, everything.
该结束了，我会说出真相 说出哈普的，你的，所有的事
-What good would that do? -lt'll end this thing.
-那样做有什么好处？ -能让这件事结束
It won't end it. You're not thinking straight.
不会结束的 你不该把想的那么天真
Will you tell the truth? You shot your partner and lied about it.
你会说出真相吗？ 是你击中了拍档，并且将此隐瞒
To them, you're a liar and a killer. You're tainted. Forever!
对他们来说，你就是骗子和凶手 你就永远有了污点！
You don't get to pick when you tell the truth. The truth is beyond that.
你不用总揪着真相不放 真相并不重要
That tape was the only proof we had a conversation outside of that room.
那卷带子不过只能证明 我们在审讯室外有过交谈
To them, I'm a writer that Kay admired.
对他们来说，我只是凯所仰慕的作家
Randy is the killer, and you're a hero cop. Your life's work is intact.
兰迪才是凶手，而你是英雄警察
Another abusive scumbag is in jail. Everything is as it should be.
又有个垃圾被关进了监狱 所有事都往正确的方向发展
Go back to Los Angeles. The case against Randy is pretty solid.
回洛杉矶去 兰迪的案子已经结束了
I can take care of everything here. I got it worked out. Go home.
这儿的事我会处理 我全会处理好，你就回去吧
Midnight of your sixth night. You broke my record, Will.
整整六天没睡觉 你破了我的记录，威尔
-Randy Stetz. He was an asshole. -You knew him as a kid?
-兰迪史特兹，他是个混蛋 -你是打小就认识他吧？
-Dads were on the same boat. -Bad seed.
-我们的父亲在同条船上工作 -是个坏种
How do you like our beer?
觉得我们这儿的啤酒怎么样？
What Dormer needs is a little shuteye.
多默需要的还是闭会眼
-White nights getting to you? -Hasn't been easy.
-适应白夜了吗？ -不会那么容易
-Better than winter. -Got that right.
-至少比冬天好 -说的是
-Sun barely comes up for five months. -Like being sucked into a black hole.
-太阳只出来五个月 -其他时候就象是被塞进了黑洞
-Hey, Nancy Drew. You hear? We got him. -Rich found the gun.
-神探南茜，听说了吗？我们抓到他了 -里奇找到了那把枪
-Something's on her mind. -I found this on the beach.
-她好象心不在焉 -这是我在海滩找到的
-What is it? -Shell casing, 9mm.
-是什么？ -是弹壳，9毫米口径的
The murder weapon was a.38. None of us carries a 9mm.
凶枪是点38口径 我们中没人用9毫米口径吧？
Or backup weapon, right?
或是后备武器？
Get a hobby, would you?
轻松点行嘛？
It's a legitimate point, isn't it, detective?
这是例行公事，对吗，探长？
This case is closed, Ellie. Hold the fort, boys. I'll go find a men's room.
这桩案子已经结束了 继续玩吧，孩子们，我回去睡了
Relieve myself of your fine Alaskan beer.
阿拉斯加啤酒让我轻松不少
Do you want a beer or something?
要来瓶啤酒吗？
No, thanks.
不，谢了
-He's good people, right? -Don't get carried away.
-他真是个好人 -别扯远了
What has two thumbs and loves blowjobs?
谁有两个拇指还喜欢口交的？
-I don't know. -This guy.
-不知道 -是这家伙
It's been something, Dormer.
终于结束了，多默
It's been really great working with you.
能和你共事真是太好了
-Run Will to the airport? -I gotta pick up the letters.
-你送威尔去机场？ -我还得去取信件
In Umkumiut--
去务库姆特--
At his lake house. Dormer will have to leave my car at the dock.
去他的湖边小屋 多默把我的车停在码头就行
-lf that's okay with you? -Yeah, it's fine.
-没关系吧？ -好的
It's been a pleasure.
很荣幸
Get some sleep.
好好休息
Detective Dormer.
多默探长
What is it?
什么事？
Someone's complaining about the noise. Says he can't sleep.
有客人投诉你这儿声音太大 让他没办法休息
Something wrong?
有什么问题？
It's so fucking bright in here.
这儿真是太亮了
No, it's dark in here.
不，这儿很黑
Will you please...?
能不能…？
There's this guy, Wayne Dobbs, 24. Works part time at a copy store.
曾经有个叫韦恩道比斯的家伙，24岁 在家复印店里做兼职
Every day he watches this 8-year-old boy...
每天他都看着那个八岁的小男孩
...waiting for his carpool across the street.
穿过马路去等车
-This is one of your cases? -Yeah. Hap and me.
-那也是你破过的案子？ -对，哈普和我一起破的
A year and a half ago.
是一年半前的事
For six months, he watches this kid.
有六个月的时间里，他一直注意着那孩子
Finally gets up the nerve.
最后他终于有了胆量
He goes down, grabs that boy before the carpool comes...
他在车来之前冲过马路抓住那孩子
...takes him back to his apartment...
把他架回自己的公寓
...and keeps him there for three days.
将他在那儿关了三天
He tortures him...
他折磨那小孩
...and makes him do things.
逼他做事
And, finally, he's had enough. He gets a rope.
最后等他玩够了 他就拿来了绳子
He hangs the boy in a storage space in the basement of the building.
把那男孩吊死在地下室的储藏间里
But he didn't do it right.
但他做的不够干净
Little boy's neck didn't break, so he dangled there for a while...
小男孩的脖子没有断 所以他就被那样挂在那里
...and then died finally from the shock.
最后在昏迷中死去
Landlord found the body five days later.
屋主是在五天后发现的尸体
The second I met this guy, Dobbs, I knew he was guilty.
见到那个道比斯的那刻 我就知道他是凶手
That's what I do. That's my job. I assign guilt.
逮捕凶手是我的工作 我被派审理此案
You find the evidence...
一般都需要找到证据
...figure out who did it, and then you go get them and put them away.
但是分析出是谁做的 再把那人送上法庭
This time there wasn't enough evidence. And it's reasonable doubt to a jury...
但这次的证据并不充分 陪审团的人就开始怀疑
...because a jury never met a child murderer before.
因为陪审团成员 从未接触过幼童谋杀案
But I have.
可是我有
Anyway....
总之….
I went and took some blood samples from the boy's dead body...
我从那孩子的尸体上取来血液样本
...and I planted them...
把那些血
...in Dobbs' apartment.
撒在道比斯的公寓里
I could feel it there.
我还清楚记得当时的情形
This is gonna catch up with me.
这样一来就使我麻烦上身
-I don't do things like that. -So how did it catch up with you?
-我一般不那样做事 -会给你带来怎样的麻烦？
Internal Affairs is coming down on our department.
内部调查科盯上了我们组
Hap, he was gonna cut a deal...
哈普他同意接受交易
...and bring me straight into it.
将我的事供给他们
They would've reopened Dobbs' case, he would've walked.
他们会给道比斯翻案， 那样他又会获得自由
Now that won't happen. And I don't know...
现在那样的事不再会发生了 我也不知道
...how I feel about that.
我该是什么感觉
But Dobbs was guilty. Dobbs needed to be convicted.
但道比斯是有罪的 他应该受到惩罚
So the end justifies the means.
最终正义得到了声张
Right?
对吗？
-I'm in no position to judge. -Why not?
-我不想去评判 -为什么？
Two kinds of people live in Alaska.
在阿拉斯加住着两种人
The ones who are born here, and the ones who come here to escape something.
一种是土生土长在这儿 另一种来这儿是为了逃避
I wasn't born here.
我并不是出生在这儿
Why don't you tell me what you think?
为什么不告诉我你的想法呢？
Here. Now. In this room. You and me.
就在这个房间里 只有你和我
Please.
说吧
I guess it's about what you thought was right at the time.
我想可能目前你这么做是对的
Then, what you're willing to live with.
那么接下去的生活 你又要信奉什么信条呢
-Nightmute Police Department. -Detective Burr.
-寂夜镇警局 -我找布勒
She's not here. She left town about 20 minutes ago to go pick up--
她出去了 大约20分钟前她离镇去拿--
-Mr. Finch. -Detective Burr.
-芬奇先生 -是布勒探员啊
-Are they friendly? -Yeah.
-它们不咬人吗？ -是的
Didn' t expect to see you this soon. Sorry about the mess, doing some work.
没想到你那么快就会来 抱歉，这里很乱
Could Kay's letters strengthen the case against Randy?
凯的信会巩固对兰迪的指控吗？
Possibly.
可能吧
Watch your head. I've done it 1 000 times.
小心头 我在这儿被磕了无数下了
Sorry about all the clutter. I am a pack-rat.
真是够乱的，我不舍得丢东西
I keep everything.
什么都会留着
I got them. Just don't know where.
我见过，可就不知道放哪儿了
-They've gotta be here somewhere. -Working on a new book?
-该就在附近的 -在写新书吗？
-Have you read any of my books? -I haven't.
-读过我写的书吗？ -没有
-She knows, Will. -Where is she?
-被她发现了，威尔 -她在哪儿？
She knows you killed Hap. You would've realized if you weren't strung out.
她知道你杀了哈普 你早就该意识到的
-The way she looks at you-- -Where is she?
-她看你的样子-- -她在哪儿？
-It's under control. -lf anything happened to her--
-我已经控制了局面 -若是她出了什么事--
She's okay.
她没事
If she talks, you're fucked. Everything you've worked for is destroyed.
她说出去你就完蛋了 你所做的一切努力也就告吹
-Now give me-- -Show me where she is. Now.
-现在给我-- -带我去看她在哪儿，快
She's okay. Listen. I mean, it's all fine.
她没事，听着 我是说都很好
Let's search this place. For the dress.
我们得搜搜这地方 来找那件外套
-What dress? -Ellie's....
-什么外套？ -埃莉的吗？
-Kay's! -You're rambling.
-是凯的！ -你说什么胡话
Ellie's here.
埃莉在这儿
-I'm taking care of us. -Us?
-这是为我们好 -我们？
-She saw the dress.
-她看到了那外套
Where'd you get us? Don't talk about us.
哪儿冒出来的什么“我们”？ 别说什么“我们”！
She's alive, Will. Ellie!
她还活着，威尔埃莉！
Hold it!
住手！
Don't move!
别动！
You shot Detective Eckhart.
你杀了艾克哈特探长
And Finch saw you do it.
而芬奇目击了此事
Did you mean to shoot Hap?
你是有意杀哈普的吗？
I don't know anymore.
我也不知道
I don't know.
我不知道
I couldn't see him through the fog, but when I got up close...
在雾里我看不见他 可当我走过去
...he was afraid of me...
他却很害怕
...and he thought I meant to do it, so maybe I did.
他认为我是有意的 可能真是这样
I just don't know anymore.
我也不知道
-Where's your gun? -He took it.
-你的枪呢？ -被他抢走了
Keep your head down.
把头低下
I got seven rounds in this clip. Make it last. Head down.
枪里还有七发子弹 小心用，记得头低下
Okay, go! Go!
好了，开始！
You forgot the wild card.
你忘了五牌
Detective Dormer!
多默探长！
I called for backup. They'll be here soon. Dormer, just hold on.
我已经呼叫支援，他们马上就到了 多默，坚持下去
Hold on.
挺住
Nobody needs to know.
没有人需要知道这事
You didn't mean to do it. I know that even if you don't.
你并非有意开枪的 你不说我也明白
No, don't. Don't.
不，不要
What?
什么？
Why?
为什么？
Don't lose your way.
别丧失你的原则
Hang on.
挺住
Dormer.
多默
Let me sleep.
让我好好睡会吧
No.
不
Just let me sleep.
让我睡会